Well, Gin Tama the anime has finally begun its second year.
(新八)ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』も
とうとう２年目に突入ですね｡
But it's not like we're actually starting... More like we somehow slyly snuck into this.
(銀時)突入っていうか
なんかうまいこと ごまかして➡
なだれ込んじまった感じだけどな｡
Correct! This is just the first step!
(神楽)そうｱﾙ！
まだ先っぽだけｱﾙ!!
Huh? We're not all set for the year?
えっ？ これ あと１年
安泰ってわけじゃないの？
You fool! Don't you know how many times Gin Tama was almost pulled?
ﾊﾞｶ言ってんじゃねえよ！
この１年 『銀魂』が➡
何度 終了の危機にさらされたと
思ってんの！
Low television ratings, changes in time slot and sponsorship, complaint letters...
(神楽)低視聴率 放送枠の移動
苦情殺到！
That's true. Thank goodness, we didn't get cancelled.
ﾎﾝﾄ よく打ち切りに
ならなかったですよね｡
Before we started airing, everyone was saying,
放送 始まる前はさ
｢これは ｺﾞｰﾙﾃﾞﾝで➡
"Hey, this is great. We'll be a hit in prime time."
数字のとれる作品だ｣とか
持ち上げといて➡
But the moment ratings went down, they turned on us!
いざ ﾌﾀを開けてみて
結果が出ないとなると➡
手のひら返しだよ！
Grown-ups are all dirty! I hate grown-ups!
(神楽)大人は みんな汚いｱﾙ｡
大人なんか 嫌いね！
They sure took us off prime time fast.
ｺﾞｰﾙﾃﾞﾝからの枠移動のときも
決断 早かったですねぇ｡
In a flash... What's this, "Isn't it a better time for JUMP viewers?"
あっという間だったな…
なにが ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ読者層的には➡
見やすい時間に
なったんじゃないの？｣だよ！
No matter how you put it, we got kicked outta prime!
どうみても都落ちだよ！
What if we keep getting bounced around and end up next to "Ladies 4"?!
(神楽)このまま どんどん時間が
繰り上げられていって➡
『ﾚﾃﾞｨｽ４』と
くっついちゃうかと思ったｱﾙ！
By the way, Otsu's song was banned from broadcast because of licensing issues.
そういえば
お通ちゃんの歌も ｸﾚｰﾑで➡
放送禁止歌に
なっちゃったんだよなぁ｡
If sponsors drop off because of such claims, this program's done for!
ｸﾚｰﾑ殺到して
ｽﾎﾟﾝｻｰ降りたら即番組終了だよ｡
They'll say they want to up ratings, announce that Gin Tama is good for diets and we're done for!
数字 上げようとして
『銀魂』にはﾀﾞｲｴｯﾄ効果があります➡
とか言って
ﾊﾞﾚたりしたら一発だよ！
You're right!
Watching anime as a diet?! There's no such thing!
(神楽)あぁ ｱﾙｱﾙ｡
ねえよ！ ｱﾆﾒ観て ﾀﾞｲｴｯﾄとか!!
The producer said his stomach  hurts and looks skinnier every time I see him!
(神楽)ﾌﾟﾛﾃﾞｭｰｻｰは 胃が痛いって
言って みるみる痩せたｱﾙ｡
That wasn't from a diet. Anyway, Gin-san, don't scare us! Our second season is about to start!
いや それ ﾀﾞｲｴｯﾄじゃないから…｡
っていうか銀さん
おどかさないでくださいよ！
これから ｱﾆﾒの２年目が
始まるってときに！
Shut up! That's the very reason I'm saying we can't let down our guard!
ﾊﾞｶﾔﾛｳ！ そんなときだからこそ
油断するなって言ってんだよ!!
If we think, "Oh boy, we can coast for one more year," we'll be dropped in six months!
これで ｢あと１年は大丈夫～！｣
とかって安心してると➡
Huh?! Seriously?!
半年で打ち切られっぞ！
えっ？ ﾏｼﾞで？
Gin-chan, is Gin Tama going to end?
(神楽)銀ちゃん
『銀魂』終わっちゃうｱﾙか？
That's why we have to do whatever we can!
そうならないために➡
ここで やるべきことは
やっておく必要がある！
Have to do...
...whatever we can?
That's...!
やるべき…｡
(神楽)こと？
それは…｡
That's?
That comes after the commercial.
(神楽/新八)それは…｡
それは CMのあとで!!
[Gin Tama the anime's second year has begun. But there's something we have to do.]
ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』が
２年目突入に際して➡
Since the anime Gin Tama is beginning its second year, there is something we must do!
やっておく必要がある
やるべきこと｡
(新八)やるべき…｡
(神楽)こと…｡
Something we...
...must do?
それは…｡
(２人)それは…｡
That's...
That's?
(銀時)それは ﾃｺ入れだ～！
Put some boost in it!
[Put some boost in it!]
ﾃｺ入れとは それは文字どおり
ﾃｺを入れることである｡
Put some boost in it! The words mean just that.
傾いた番組や ｽﾀｰﾄﾀﾞｯｼｭに
失敗した番組にﾃｺを入れ➡
Programs that have slumped or programs that didn't get a swift start get some boost...
何とか盛り返そうと
あれこれ変更を加えることである｡
and strategies are instigated to hike up its popularity.
However,
[However]
it can get rather difficult with writers in an uproar, and sometimes the boost fails.
その結果 現場が混乱したり➡
ﾗｲﾀｰが ふて腐れたり
ﾃｺ入れ自体が失敗だったり➡
何をしても 時すでに遅かったり
することが ままあるため➡
And any action can be too late. So success is never guaranteed.
成果が上がるという事例は
稀有であると言っていいだろう｡
というわけなんで➡
So speak up if you have any good ideas about how to make Gin Tama better.
これからの 『銀魂』を
どうしていくべきか➡
お前ら なんかいい方法があったら
言ってみろよ！
まぁ 手っ取り早く
お手軽に変化をつけるには➡
Well... The easiest and fastest solution is to change the title of the program.
ﾀｲﾄﾙ変えたりするのが
普通っすよね｡
例えば…｡
For example...
♪♪～
『銀魂２』とか…｡
Gin Tama 2.
♪♪～
Or Gin Tamas.
『銀魂～ズ』とか…｡
｢Ｚ｣とか ｢Ｘ｣とか
｢ｾｶﾝﾄﾞｼｰｽﾞﾝ｣とかもありますよね｡
There's also Z and X or Second Season.
[Note: X and Z, as in Dragon Ball X, etc.]
｢Ｇ｣とか ｢Ｖ｣とか
｢ﾀｰﾝＡ｣とかなんか意味あるｱﾙか？
[Note: Turn A as in Turn A Gundam.]
What's the meaning of G, V and Turn A?
うん ｢Ｖ｣は ありだと思うよ｡
Yeah, I think V stands for something.
いっそのこと最終回っぽく➡
How about we add something sad to make it seem like it's the final one?
悲壮感であおるっていうのは
どうだい？
Like "Farewell," or "Forever," or "Complete Version"?
[Note: This refers to the anime Battleship Yamato]
｢さらば｣とか ｢永遠に｣とか
｢完結編｣とかつけてさ｡
なに また ｢新たなる旅立ち｣
とかいって➡
We just have to say, "A new journey begins," and start over again.
仕切り直しゃいいんだよ｡
ちょっと銀さん… そこ まだ
ﾓﾒてるんだから まずいですよ｡
Hey Gin-san... They're still fighting about that, so don't bring it up.
いっそのこと ﾏｯｷｰに
主題歌 歌ってもらおうｱﾙ｡
I know! Let's get Makki to sing the theme song!
[Note: This refers to pop singer Noriyuki Makihara.]
だから 危ないって｡
I said they're still fighting about that!
じゃあ ｢危ない｣つながりで
｢もっと｣とか ｢またまた｣とかは？
Then how about we use, "More of" or "Again" like the Abunai series?
それなら 『たまたま銀魂』のほうが
ｺﾞﾛがいいｱﾙ｡
In that case, "Tamatama Gin Tama" sounds better.
意味わかんねえよ！
ふぅ…｡
What does that mean?!
Hmm... Well, just changing the title won't fool viewers these days.
まぁ 今どき
ﾀｲﾄﾙ変えたくらいで➡
視聴者も簡単に騙されねえか｡
If we're gonna do something, we have to go all out.
やるなら もっと
徹底的にやらねえとな｡
主役ﾛﾎﾞを変えるとか
新兵器を装着するとか➡
Like changing to a main robot or inventing new weapons. Power up in a way that's obvious.
わかりやすいﾊﾟﾜｰｱｯﾌﾟをだな…｡
ﾒｶもﾛﾎﾞも いませんよ このｱﾆﾒ｡
あっ…｡
This anime has no robots or transformers.
Oh...
｢あっ｣じゃねえよ まったく！
しようがないな…｡
Come on! You're hopeless. Maybe it's not the robot we should change, but the main character!
ﾛﾎﾞじゃなくて
主人公を変えたほうが➡
いいんじゃないの？
ﾏｼﾞでか？
Are you serious?
ｸｯｸｯｸｯ…｡
神楽ちゃん？
Kagura-chan?
(神楽)主役交代 いいじゃないか｡
(銀時/新八)えっ!?
Changing main characters sounds good.
Huh?!
だったら
来週から主役は ｱﾀｲだよ！
From next week on, I'll be the main character! We'll go forth with Gin Tama like this!
これから 『銀魂』は
こんな路線で突っ走るｱﾙ！
(鐘の音)
The man swore his eternal love.
And the woman swore to return his love.
But then...
A single gun shot...
♪♪～
["Once Upon a Time in China-Girl"]
[Gin Tama]
A chance encounter.
Two people fall in love...
And live a simple life.
But then...
One single bowl of noodles...
まだ食べてるでしょうが！
She's still eating that!
The flow of time separates the two...
♪♪～
神楽～！
銀ちゃ～ん!!
Kagura!!
Gin-chan!
Then the stage turns towards outer-space.
What could Catherine be scheming?
I said I, Catherine, will rule!
♪♪～
And, what is this? The plan to destroy earth by Otose of Teradaya?!
A young girl tossed around by fate!!
＜神楽:大江戸映画界 最高の➡
The best in the Edo film world have been gathered to create this epic drama,
[Directed by: Sonomanma Miyazaki (Puke Wars)]
[Screenplay by: Kenta Nukesaku (Alien vs Yakuza)]
[Music by: Joe Hisaishi (My Neighbor Pedro)]
[Original Story by: Gasuko Hajida (Life is full of demons, curse you!)]
ｽﾀｯﾌを結集して描く➡
一大 大河ﾄﾞﾗﾏ＞
Gin Tama: Once Upon a Time in China-Girl.
You have yet to know the real Gin Tama.
[Broadcast starts next week.]
Oh, so touching!
うぅ～っ！ 感動ｱﾙ～！
(お登勢)勝手に➡
Quit using my name without permission!
人のこと 使ってんじゃないよ～｡
(お登勢)なんだよ…
こういう肝心なときに➡
Hey, what's this? At times like these, why don't you come to me for help?
どうして 助けを求めないんだい？
Otose, when'd you get here?
お登勢さん いつのまに…｡
Running a store and an anime are basically the same things.
店もｱﾆﾒも 同じことだよ｡
客の欲しがっているものを
提供する｡
You give customers what they want. And supplement whatever's missing.
今 足りないものを補う｡
足りないものを…？
What's missing?
I've been thinking, the things you do are childish.
常々 思ってたんだけどね➡
ｱﾝﾀらの やることは
ｶﾞｷ臭いんだよ｡ ﾊﾞｶも いいけどね➡
Fools are fine. But it gets pretty boring after a while.
それだけじゃ
飽きられて 当然だろ｡
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)さわやかな お色気が
足りないってことですよ｡
She means you lack a refreshing sexiness.
夢を与え 幸せを与える｡
Evoke dreams, evoke happiness... That's the kind of story you must create.
そういう作品に なんないと…｡
(お登勢)いっけな～い！
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)遅刻 遅刻～！
Oh no!
I'm late, I'm late!
(お登勢)あん！
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｲｯﾀｰｲ！
Oww!
[Note: Japanese School Girl slang for Catherine]
Owww! No way! It's Cassapee!
(お登勢)ｱｲﾀﾀﾀ…｡
やだ！ ｷｬｻｯﾍﾟじゃな～い！
Otossechi, are you late too?
[Note: Japanese School Girl slang for Otose]
お登勢っちも 遅刻？
＜お登勢:２人は
かぶき町中学に通う…＞
These two attend Kabukicho middle school...
...and are childhood friends.
＜ｷｬｻﾘﾝ:幼なじみ＞
＜お登勢:ごく 普通の➡
They're average girls, but...
女の子だけど…＞
＜秘密があるの｡ それは…＞
They have a secret, which is...
(お登勢)これは！
(ｼｸﾞﾅﾙの音)
Oh no...
There's someone about to get their soul sucked out of their butt.
[Note: In folklore, kappa or water imps will suck out your entrails/life force from your anus.]
尻子玉を
抜かれそうな人がいるわ！
♪♪～
Collecting debts! No mercy!
(２人)売り掛け 取り立て
容赦しな～い！
(お登勢)そう！
Yes! These two are...
２人は…！
[Note: Pretty Cure parody.]
Magical Mature Females! We are Tama Cure Silver Soul!
(２人)魔法熟女！
２人は ﾀﾏｷｭｱ！ ｼﾙﾊﾞｰｿｳﾙ！
(２人)あぁ～っ！
♪♪～
(化け物)ﾑｰさん！
We...
私たちは！
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)負けない!!
...will not lose!!
(２人)ﾅｯﾂ ｷｽﾁｮｺ 柿の種！
Nuts, Kiss Chocolates, Persimmon Seeds!
(２人)かわきものなら 再利用！
We'll fix things that are dried and old!
♪♪～
The customer's always right!
(２人)お客様は 神様です！
♪♪～
＜ お登勢:２人の友情ﾊﾟﾜｰが
世界を守る！＞
The friendship these two share will protect the world!
(２人)２人は ﾀﾏｷｭｱ！ ｼﾙﾊﾞｰｿｳﾙ!!
We are Tama Cure Silver Soul!
(３人)ｵｴｰｯ！
ｵﾚたちを 吐き殺す気か！
Do you want us all to vomit to death?!
You can keep fighting till the end of the century!
お前たちは
世紀末を戦ってりゃ 十分ｱﾙ～！
You're revolting!
(神楽)ﾕｱｰ ｼｮｯｸね!!
夢を与えるより➡
Instead of evoking dreams, you're evoking fear and despair!
恐怖と絶望を
与えてるじゃねえか！
(桂)同感だな｡
んっ!?
I agree.
Zura...
ﾂﾞﾗ…｡
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない｡ 桂だ｡
It's not Zura. It's Katsura.
How long has he been sitting here? And he's totally ready to join the conversation.
《いつのまに 座ってたんだ？
しかも
会話に参加する気満々だ～！》
If you're going for it, you need something cutting edge. How about this?
(桂)
やはり 狙うなら 最先端だろう｡
こんなのは どうだ？
[Check it out!]
♪♪～
(近藤)うら～っ!!
よぅ ﾂﾞﾗ どうしたなりか？
Yo Zura... Wazzup?
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない 桂だ｡
It ain't Zura. It's Katsura.
What about work?
仕事は？
今は ﾗｰﾒﾝ屋で働いている｡
I work at a ramen shop right now.
Huh? Fired?
えっ？ ｸﾋﾞ？
I'm going to save up my money and leave this town someday.
(さっちゃん)
いつかは お金 貯めて➡
この街を 出ていくわ｡
[You're genius.]
[Your dreams will certainly come true.]
(拍手)
Love... It can be so strong...
♪♪(桂)｢愛 それは強く｣
Love... It can be so sweet...
♪♪｢愛 それは 甘く｣
♪♪(２人)｢ﾗﾗﾗﾗﾗﾗ｣
[The Pork Back Rib (Rose) of Versailles]
♪♪～
If you believe, dreams will always come true.
＜桂:信じていれば
必ず 夢は叶う＞
[Takarazura Opera Company -Gin Tama-]
…というのは どうだろう？
How about something like that?
…どうって
いいわけないじゃないですか｡
Something like that won't work. Just what is your dream, anyway?
だいたい ｱﾝﾀの夢って なんなの!?
(ﾁｬｲﾑ)
あれ？ 姉上｡
３人が一緒なんて 珍しいですね｡
Huh? Sister!
How unusual for the three of you to be together.
We're not together, Shin-chan.
(お妙)一緒というわけじゃ
ないのよ 新ちゃん｡
We just met up by chance.
そこで
偶然 一緒になっただけなの｡
I don't meet up with anyone other than Gin-san around town.
(さっちゃん)私 銀さん以外の人と
外で 会ったりしないから…｡
I've never heard that before. And what?
聞いてないって｡ なんだか
また 面倒なの増えたなぁ｡
More troublesome guys? What're you doing here?
なにしに来たんだ ﾃﾒｴら！
Isn't it obvious?
決まってるじゃないの～！
(長谷川)なんか➡
I heard you're thinking of a boosting strategy. The least you could've done was called me.
ﾃｺ入れ 考えてるんだって？
水臭いなぁ｡
ひと声
かけてくれればいいのによ｡
えっ？
なんか ｱｲﾃﾞｱあるんですか？
What? You have an idea?
This sort of thing is my specialty. I mean, I'm boosting my life, you know?
こういうの おっさん 得意だから｡
なんせ 人生 ﾃｺ入れしてんだぜ
こっちは｡
いいか？ ﾃｺ入れってのはな…｡
Now listen, the way you change...
Stimulation! Stimulation brings on more stimulation. That's the base power of boosting!
刺激よ！ 刺激が 刺激を呼び➡
それこそが
ﾃｺ入れの原動力になるのよ！
For the second year, you need masochism. This era is crying out for sadism!
２年目は 脱Ｍ宣言！
時代は ﾄﾞＳを求めているの!!
♪♪～
[Banned in 42 states in the United States.]
[A chilling, suspenseful thriller.]
[NEVER watch this movie alone.]
(悲鳴)
If pushing won't work, trying pulling. How about my idea for sadism? And shoot for prime ti--!
押してもﾀﾞﾒなら 引いてみろ｡
ﾄﾞＳな新展開ってどう？
目指せ ｺﾞｰﾙﾃﾞﾝ！
それは 新展開じゃなくて➡
That's not going to make us better. You'll only get us moved to fringe late-night programming!
新境地だろう ｱﾝﾀの！
今度は 深夜に
枠移動になるじゃんか!!
Besides, how can something like that be approved, you idiot?!
てゆうか こんなの
ありえるか ﾊﾞｶ野郎｡
あ… もう やっぱり なんだ
かんだ言って Ｍのほうがいい｡
Oh... I think I prefer masochism, after all.
いや だからさ｡ こういうのは➡
Hey, just leave these things to me. Huh?!
おっさんに任せとけって｡
That just won't do, Sarutobi-san.
こんなんじゃ ﾀﾞﾒなのよ 猿飛さん｡
なんですって？
What?
この番組に足りないのは 王道よ｡
What this program lacks is Struggle.
努力と友情｡
Victory and Friendship.
And when we defeat a foe, a stronger one is waiting in the wings.
そして 強敵を倒すと
さらに 強敵が待っているという➡
熱い冒険が 少年の心をつかむの｡
That's the kind of exciting adventure grabbing kids these days.
＜お妙:いにしえより伝えられた➡
From ancient times, there have been tales about the seven gems...
７つの玉を探すべく集まった➡
and the six brave warriors who searched for them.
[Note: This refers to the famous legend "Satomi Hakkenden."]
６人の勇者たち…＞
Let's go!!
いくわよ！
♪♪～
うぐぁ…｡
The warm friendship of youth...
＜若者たちの熱き友情＞
Never mind me, go!
ｵﾚのことは いい… 行け！
私が 必ず守ってやる！
うらぁ～！
I will not fail to protect you!
がったい！
Bankai!
[Note: reference to a term from the anime "Bleach."]
どりゃあ～！
Gum-gum!
[Note: reference to a term from the anime "One Piece."]
(お妙)ｺﾞﾑｺﾞﾑ～！
はぁ～っ！
＜今年度 最高のﾌｧﾝﾀｼﾞｰ＞
The ultimate fantasy of the year!
Gin Tama the Movie: DragonBleaPeace!
No way! There's way too many risky references!
できるか！
危ないのが そこかしこに➡
仕掛けられてるじゃんかぁ！
We'll capture the hearts of the youth with this!
少年のﾊｰﾄも ｶﾞｯﾁﾘ つかめるわ｡
And before that, the higher-ups will grab hold of our hearts and crush them.
その前に ｵﾚたちのﾊｰﾄが➡
偉い人に
握り潰されそうなんですけど｡
That's why...just leave it to me.
だからさぁ おっさんに
任せておけばいいんだよ｡
こういうのは
やっぱ 輝きに満ちた➡
At times like these, you need a glowing success story.
ｻｸｾｽｽﾄｰﾘｰが受けんだよ｡
["You can't watch this masterpiece without bawling your eyes out." - Daily Edo Newspaper]
The entire world cried.
＜長谷川:世界じゅうが泣いた｡
["Bravo!! This movie will definitely change history." - O-Edo Weekly Newspaper]
The touching success story...Madao.
感動のｻｸｾｽｽﾄｰﾘｰ｡
[A must see for the broken-hearted. I've never seen such a compelling human drama." - Edo Times Newspaper]
『MADAO』…＞
Starting tomorrow, you don't have to come in.
(役員)ｷﾐねぇ
明日から来なくていいから｡
♪♪～
A man who has lost all hope...
and a man who forgot about love.
For them, a strange journey begins.
♪♪～
(笑い声)
The true way of life is found here. A Dumb Old Retarded Dork...
＜長谷川:真実の生き方が
そこにある｡
まるで ﾀﾞﾒなおっさん…
Madao. Road of Gin Tama.
って なに これぇ！
What the heck?!
誰？ ｵﾚの妄想 改ざんしたの｡
Who changed my delusions?! It's not a success story at all.
全然 ｻｸｾｽｽﾄｰﾘｰじゃないじゃん！
No, this may turn into a hit.
いやぁ これは案外
受けるかもしれないｱﾙ｡
今の世相を斬る
社会派ｱﾆﾒに昇格かもよ｡
It may boost the image of social commentary anime.
賞とか とっちゃうかもよ｡
って聞いてねえし！
No one told me!!
Let's go with Tama Cure!
(お登勢)だからやっぱり ﾀﾏｷｭｱで｡
(神楽)なに言ってるｱﾙ ｱﾀｲの！
No way! We should use my story.
(長谷川)あぁっ！
おっさんのは まだ…｡
Hey, no one's heard my sto--!
The age for sadism is now!
(お妙)努力 根性 勇気よ！
It's perseverance and courage!
The jig is up!
(土方)御用改めである！
Hey, hey... What's the big idea? Were you invited? Or are you here to make trouble?
おいおい
どういう風の吹き回しですか？
招かざる客ですか
嫌がらせですか｡
Really. No one called any one of you here.
っていうか お前ら 誰一人として
呼んでないんですけど｡
We got word that Katsura is here. Where is he?
ここに 桂がいるという
通報があった｡
どこに いる？
知らねえなぁ｡
I dunno. Go home! Who gave you permission to stay?!
っていうか 帰れ｡
誰に断って ここにいやがる｡
I don't know. Anyway, turn over Katsura! Otherwise, we'll haul all of you in!
知らねえな！
っていうか桂 差し出せ｡
じゃねえと お前らも
まとめて しょっぴくぞ！
We'll haul you guys! Don't think you can do whatever you please just because you're the police!
しょっぴかれるのは
お前のほうだ！
警察だからって なんだって
許されると思ったら 大間違いだ！
What?!
なんだとっ！
Anyway, what are you all discussing?
(沖田)それはそうと
皆さん お揃いで➡
いってえ 何のご相談ですかい？
Well, Gin Tama is going into its second year and we were discussing what should be done.
あぁ それがですね｡
『銀魂』も ２年目に入りまして➡
これから どうしたものかって
相談を｡
ｹｯ ﾊﾞｶﾊﾞｶしい｡
How stupid!
そんなﾊﾞｯｻﾘ！
ﾃｺ入れが成功しないと➡
Don't be so blunt! Unless we boost up ratings and succeed, we're all going down!
みんな 共倒れなんですよ！
You won't be able to suck on your beloved mayonnaise!
大好きなﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞだって
吸えなくなるね！
ﾃｺ入れか…｡
Boost it up?
(拍手)
[World Gin Tama Cooking Show]
ﾊﾊﾊ… ｢銀魂料理ｼｮｰ｣へ ようこそ｡
Welcome to the World Gin Tama Cooking Show. Now I'm going to introduce some great dishes.
さぁ 今日は
とびっきりの料理を紹介だ｡
First, get some mayonnaise ready. Right on a plate.
まず始めに ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞを用意する｡
それを 皿に盛り付けて…｡
ん～ん｡
(笑い声)
ｽﾃｨｰﾌﾞ ｽﾃｨｰﾌﾞ わかったよ｡
Steve, Steve, I know, I know. Don't keep tasting it, right?
味見ばっかりしてないで
早く進めろっていうんだろ？
Then you put more mayonnaise and...It's done.
この上に
更に ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞをかけて出来上がりだ｡
Oh!
(歓声)
This is the Gin Tama Cooking Show! See you next week
｢銀魂料理ｼｮｰ｣ また来週｡
(拍手)
That's it? You coward!
(神楽)それでも いいっていうのか
薄情者！
ｺﾞﾎﾝｯ そんな話は 局長に頼め｡
I'll ask the Chief about this!
Kondo-san? Well, I don't think he needs to know.
近藤さんですか？
いやぁ あの人は別に｡
ｺﾞﾘﾗの話は いいね｡
Forget about the gorilla.
No, don't be shy. I fully understand all your concerns!
(近藤)いや 遠慮することはない｡
諸君らの悩み しかと受け取った｡
Not another troublemaker.
また 面倒くさいﾔﾂが出てきたよ｡
Just relax and leave it to me
まぁ ここは 大船に
乗ったつもりで ｵﾚに任せろ｡
Boosting it up is done like this...
ﾃ… ﾃｺ入れとは
こういうふうにするもんだ｡
＜近藤:ある夜
仕事の重圧と不満から➡
One night, due to the pressures and worries of his work, Isao Kondo ran away from the Shinsengumi.
近藤 勲は真選組を飛び出した｡
[Isao Kondo, Shinsengumi Chief]
And he encountered a girl in town.
そこで出会ったのは 一人の町娘＞
[Tae Shimura, Press Reporter]
(いびき)
＜近藤:男が
新撰組の局長だと 知った娘は➡
Upon discovering the man was the Chief of the Shinsengumi,
she took him to Kabukicho hoping for the scoop of the century.
世紀のｽｸｰﾌﾟをものにすべく
男を家に連れ帰り➡
かぶき町を案内する＞
うわっ！
ｷｬｰ!!
However...
＜近藤:しかし
別れのときがやってくる＞
The time to part had arrived.
＜近藤:最後に２人は
本来の立場で言葉を交わす＞
At the very end, the two exchange words as their true selves.
I have a question for the Chief. What is your favorite town?
局長さんに質問です｡
好きな町はどこですか？
かぶき町です！
なんといっても かぶき町です!!
Kabukicho. It's definitely Kabukicho.
＜近藤:ﾛﾏﾝﾁｯｸ ﾗﾌﾞｽﾄｰﾘｰ…
Romantic Love Story
Roman Gin Tama.
[Note: Refers to "Roman Holiday" with Gregory Peck, as the reporter, and Audrey Hepburn, as the princess.]
ｳｸﾞｸﾞ… どう？ どう!?
How's that? Huh?!
なにが 『ﾛｰﾏの銀魂』だぁ!!
『ｺﾞﾘﾗの脱走』だろうが！
Roman Gin Tama?! Are you crazy?!
More like the "Escape of the Gorilla!"
そもそも ﾛｰﾏじゃなくて
かぶき町じゃねえか!!
Besides, it isn't Rome! It's Kabukicho!
Wait, wait, wait! I have another idea too.
待て待て待て！
別なｱｲﾃﾞｱもあるんだ!!
Otae-san! Oh, Otae-san! Wherefore art thou, Otae-san?!
お妙さん！ おぉ お妙さん!!
どうして
あなたは お妙さんなの！
＜近藤:『お妙と近藤』
結ばれぬ恋の物語＞
Otae and Kondo:
The Story of Two Star-Crossed Lovers.
[Otae and Kondo]
Enough!
もう いいわ！
しかも自分が姫かよ！
He's taking the princess's lines!
(神楽)姫というより ｺﾞﾘね
ｺﾞﾘというより ｺﾞﾘﾗね！
He's not a princess, he's a gorilla!
(お妙)ｲﾔだわ近藤さん｡
Oh, Kondo-san!
ｼｪｰｸｽﾋﾟｱに失礼よ｡ っていうか➡
You're being rude to Shakespeare...
Not only that...
私に対する 最高級の侮辱だわ!!
But it's also a supreme insult to me!
死刑執行よ!!
I sentence you to death!
Chief, if it's not shocking and exciting, it won't sell.
(沖田)局長… 昨今➡
刺激と衝撃がないと
ｳｹねえんでさあ｡
I have an excellent idea.
ｵﾚに妙案がありますぜ｡
(沖田)うあぁぁ…｡
[We're not able to show you the rest. Please wait a moment.]
♪♪～
ﾎﾟｲｰﾝ… ｾﾁｱｰ！
Poinsettia!
S-Sorry! I didn't say it on purpose.
ｺﾛ！ ｺﾛ ごめんよ
わざとじゃなかった…｡
ｸﾞﾌﾌﾌ… 鴨南蛮 鴨南蛮 鴨南蛮…｡
Kamonanba kamonanba kamonanba.
みんな しっかりしろ
ただの心理攻撃だ！
Everyone, hang in there! It's just a psychological attack on our senses!
何かに つかまれ！
Grab onto something!
な… すみません｡
(ﾊﾀ皇子)なんじゃ銀髪｡
I'm sorry.
[Note: "Ginpatsu" means "Silver Hair."]
What is it, Ginpatsu?
Oh, you were just so close.
いやぁ 近くにあったものだから｡
You guys were so noisy, Koro ran away while we were taking a walk. What's the big fuss?
お前らが うるさいから➡
散歩中のｺﾛが
逃げてしまったではないか｡
なにを そんなに
騒いでおるのじゃ｡
Well...
あの… 実は｡
I see...trying to get some boost, eh? Then I'll give you a brilliant idea.
なるほど ﾃｺ入れか｡
ならば余が
すばらしいｱｲﾃﾞｱを出してやろう｡
いや 何も言ってないからね
説明すんでないから｡
No, I didn't say anything. I'm not finished explaining.
It's news. What the people of the world need is love...
ようは ﾆｰｽﾞだろ！
世の中のものに必要なのは
ﾗﾌﾞ ｱﾝﾄﾞ ﾋﾟｰｽだぞよ｡
and peace.
An expansive meadow...
＜ﾊﾀ皇子:広大な草原｡
秘境の ｼﾞｬﾝｸﾞﾙ＞
A secret jungle...
It is there, a prince...
＜ﾊﾀ皇子:そこに生まれた
１匹の… いや１人の皇子｡
was born...
Months and years pass and the prince grows up into a fine young man.
年月がたち
たくましく成長していく皇子＞
♪♪～
ｱ～ｱｱ～｡
＜ﾊﾀ皇子:しかし…＞
But one day...
(銃声)
(近藤)ﾊﾟｵｰﾝ！
＜ﾊﾀ皇子:平和なｼﾞｬﾝｸﾞﾙに
危機が迫る＞
In the peaceful jungle...
...danger approaches.
(みんな)ｳｷｰ！
ﾊｯ！
(みんな)ｳｷｷ…！
う～ん… よし！
All right.
(銀時たち)皇子～！
＜ﾊﾀ皇子:今 大宇宙を舞台に➡
Now, with vast space as his stage,
ｼﾞｬﾝｸﾞﾙ皇子の
新たな相棒探しの旅が始まる！＞
the Prince of the Jungle begins a new journey to find new friends!
ｱ～ｱｱ～｡
The Prince of Jungle.
And where's the "love and peace"?! You abandoned your friends!
って どこが ﾗﾌﾞ ｱﾝﾄﾞ ﾋﾟｰｽだよ！
仲間 見捨ててんじゃん！
In life, you have to know when to give up.
人生 あきらめが肝心じゃ｡
おい 猿か ｵﾚは猿か!?
Hey! A monkey? You made me a monkey?!
私もｲﾔよ 猿は新八だけでいいね！
I don't want that either! Shinpachi is the only monkey!
ﾎﾞｸはいいって どういうことだよ!?
Only me?! What do you mean?!
やっぱりｵﾚのが いちばん
まともだったんじゃないの？
My story is still the best.
これだから素人は！
自分の面見て 言えや!!
That's why I hate amateurs! Speak for yourself!
やはりここは みなの意見の➡
I think when we look at all the options, my idea is the best.
最大公約数として ｵﾚのｱｲﾃﾞｱを｡
つうか 誰だ？ お前｡
(桂)通りがかりの ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝｶﾂｰﾗだ｡
Just who are you?
Just passing by, I'm Captain Katsura.
誰だか知らんが
心に秘めた ｵﾚの企画のほうが…｡
Whoever you are, my idea has the most heart and effort.
どうせ 『世界の犬のｴｻ』
みたいな番組だろう？
Isn't it going to be just another "The Dog Food of the World" kind of program?
Shut up! Hey!
ﾃﾒｴ やんのか ｺﾗ!!
(近藤)ﾄｼ やめろ！
Toshi, stop! My idea is the best.
ここは中を取って ｵﾚの案で｡
No way, gorilla! My idea is best.
ありえねえよ ｺﾞﾘﾗ！
ここは やっぱり私の案で｡
No, we should go by age and that's me.
いや 年長者をたてて ｱﾀｼの案で｡
いや 余の案がよいじゃろう｡
(さっちゃん)いいえ 私の｡
No, my idea is the best.
No, mine...
My success story is...!
ｵﾚの ｻｸｾｽｽﾄｰﾘｰの…｡
ちょっと みんな！
Hey everyone... I haven't even had a word in edgewise.
ﾎﾞｸなんか まだ
案すら出してないんですよ！
Shut up, four-eyes! You don't even have any character goods on sale, so shut up!
[Note: Character goods as in tie-in merchandise.]
うっせえよ ﾒｶﾞﾈ！
ろくに ｷｬﾗｸﾀｰｸﾞｯｽﾞも
発売されてねえくせに➡
黙ってろ！
うっ… 気にしてたのに｡
And that's been really bothering me, too...
♪♪～
うるせぇぇ！
Shut up!!
I'd expected it, but this is really turning into a lot of drama.
予想はしてたが➡
やっぱり ｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞの展開に
なっちまったな｡
Anyway, since I'm the main character, I will decide!
だが最後は
主人公である このｵﾚが➡
ﾋﾞｼｰｯと決めさせてもらうぜ！
Gin-chan...
銀ちゃん！
そうですね➡
You're right. You should make a firm decision right now!
ここは銀さんに
ﾋﾞｼｯと決めてもらいましょう！
Leave it to me. This is my answer!
あぁ 任せとけ｡
ｺｲﾂが ｵﾚの答えだ 正座して見ろ！
Sit and watch!
Huh?
あれ？
何も始まらないｱﾙよ｡
Nothing's started.
始まらないっていうか ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞまで
終わっちゃったんですけど…｡
Not only did it not start, the ending is already over.
(ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ)
あ～あ… やっぱりｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞだよ｡
Oh... See? Nothing's settled.
(ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ)まっ 予想はしてたがな｡
I figured as much. It was a bad idea to leave it up to you guys in the first place.
だいたい お前らに任せたのが
間違いだったよ｡
(桂)な… なにを
言っているのだ？ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
What're you saying, Elizabeth?
今日は ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽじゃねえんだよ！
I'm not Elizabeth today.
(桂)えっ？ 誰？
も… もしかして監督…｡
Huh? Who are you?
C-Could you be...the direc...?
というわけで すみません…｡
That's right. I'm sorry. I'll do it right from next week on. I'm really sorry.
来週から
ちゃんと やりますから…｡
ﾎﾝﾄすみません…｡
[Preview]
No way. This can't be happening. You've gotta be kidding!
["Milk Should be Served at Body Temperature."]
[Gin-san has an illegitimate child?! Is he guilty?!]
[We did it because I was upset. Now we apologize. Next time we're aiming for a serious Gin Tama.]
(栄純)よっしゃあ！ 俺はやるぜ！
だっはっはっは！
(礼)あのﾊﾞｶ…｡